aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Tobe
토베
Targeted Gaku
노려진 가쿠
Destroyer of Space Demakka Seijin
Appears
우주의 파괴자 데맛카 성인
등장
I feel possessed...
귀신이 붙었어...
100 yen for one Dagwon sign...
다그온 사인은 100엔...
Gaku, please wake up.
가쿠 군, 일어나세요
Gaku.
가쿠 군
Don't call me Gaku.
가쿠 가쿠 하지마
I am Manabu...
난 마나부...
Wh- what the-?!
뭐, 뭐야?!
I am Demakka Seijin.
저는 데맛카 성인
Demakka Seijin? An alien?!
데맛카 성인?
우주인?!
Do- don't come near me!
오, 오지마!
Just a moment!
기다려 주세요!
Di- did you al- also came to invade the Earth?!
너, 너도 지구를 치, 침략하러 온 거야?!
Invade? Nonsense!
침략? 다, 당치도 않아요
I ran away from Sargasso gangs.
저는 사르갓소 녀석들에게서 도망쳐 왔습니다
Sargasso...
사르갓소라니...
What is it?
그게 뭐야?
It is a space prison where vicious criminals who disturb planets are taken in.
별들을 어지럽히는 흉악 범죄자들을 수용한 우주 감옥
That is Sargasso.
그것이 사르갓소입니다
But those aliens rose up and took over Sargasso.
하지만 우주인들은 반란을 일으켜, 사르갓소를 빼앗았습니다
I see. They all were villains of space!
그렇구나. 그녀석들 모두 우주의 악당들이었어
And unfortunately during space travel, I was attacked by them, so I had to come to this Earth.
그리고 우주 여행중이었던 저는 운 나쁘게도 녀석들에게 습격당해 이 지구에...
I understand! You came to ask for a help to Dagwon!
알겠다! 다그온에게 도움을 요청하러 왔구나
Dagwon? What is it?
다그온!이 뭔가요?
-Huh? You don't know?
-Y-yes.
-에? 몰라?
-예
Are you sure that you don't know at all?
정말로 정말 몰라?
I am sure that I don't know at all.
정말로 정말 모릅니다
Please tell me.
가르쳐 주세요
Who is Dagwon? Will it help me?
다그온이란 누구?
절 구해 줄까요?
Should I tell you, or what?
가르쳐 줄까? 어쩔까?
Please don't tease me!
너무 그러지 말아요
I'll have something in return.
꼭 답례할테니까요
I'll tell you if then.
할 수 없지
If you want to know that badly, I'll let you know!
그렇게 알고 싶다면, 가르쳐 주지
Dagwon is...
다그온은...
... a brave hero of justice who protects the Earth!
지구를 지키는 정의의 용자야
Fire En!
파이어 엔
Turbo Kai!
터보 카이
Armor Shin!
아머 신
Wing Yoku!
윙 요쿠
Shadow Ryu!
섀도우 류
Drill Geki!
드릴 게키
Those six with Dag Tectors are the super heroes with awesome powers and techniques.
다그 텍터를 입은 6명은 엄청난 힘과 기술을 가진 슈퍼 히어로야
Are you alright?
괜찮니?
Please sign this!
싸, 싸, 싸, 싸, 싸인해 주세요!
Fire Bird Attack!
파이어 버드 어택!
Turbo Wheel Attack!
터보 호일 어택!
Breast Motor Cannon!
브레스트 모터 캐논!
Blizzard Hurricane!
블리자드 허리케인!
Big Spiral Whirlwind Slash!
대회전 검풍참!
Drill Crush!
드릴 크러시!
If a bad alien gets caught by Dag Tector, it'll be done for in no time!
다그 텍터에 걸리면, 나쁜 우주인 따윈 순식간에 끝장이지
Wow! That's reassuring!
오옷! 그것 참 듬직하군요
But...
하지만...
Gaku, no, Mr. Manabu,
가쿠... 아니, 마나부 님
What happens if the opponent makes itself gigantic? Wouldn't we be done for instead then?
만약 상대가 거대화하면 오히려 이쪽이 끝장나지 않을까요?
No need to worry at all!
쯧쯧, 걱정할 필요 없어
Dagwon has a much more amazing ability.
다그온에겐 훨씬 더 엄청난 능력이 있어
An amazing ability?
엄청난 능력?
-Do you want to know?
-I do want to.
-듣고 싶어?
-듣고 싶어요
Then listen carefully.
그럼 잘 들으라구
Dagwon's super amazing ability!
다그온의 초 엄청난 능력!
The name is...
그 이름하여...
Merging Fusion!
융합합체다!
Merging Fusion?!
융합합체?!
Dag Tectors can perform Merging Fusion with its Dag Vehicle and become a brave robot.
다그 텍터는 다그 비클과 융합합체해서 용자 로봇이 될 수 있어
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Fire!
다그 파이어
Fire Blaster!
파이어 블래스터!
Shoot!
슛!
Isn't it awesome?
어때, 굉장하지?
It really is magnificent!
정말 대단합니다
-But...
-But?
-하지만...
-하지만?
It is kinda unreliable when there is only one who can become a giant...
거대화할 수 있는 게 한명 뿐이어서는 조금 불안한 감이...
You have no brains, for an alien, as expected!
우주인 주제에 머리 참 나쁘구만
Of course other members can also perform Merging Fusion!
다른 멤버들도 당연히 융합합체할 수 있지
What?!
그럴수가!
The three members of Liner Team perform Merging Fusion with Dag Vehicles with the form of bullet trains.
라이너 팀의 3명은 신간선 형태의 다그 비클과 융합합체하지
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Turbo!
다그 터보
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Armor!
다그 아머
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Wing!
다그 윙
We did this!
우리도 할 수 있었군요!
Let's test our power!
우리 힘을 시험해 주마!
Blizzard Typhoon!
블리자드 타이푼!
And the new member who recently joined the Liner Team is Dag Drill!
그리고 라이너 팀에 새로 가담한 동료가 바로 다그 드릴이야!
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Drill!
다그 드릴
Is that the boss?
저녀석이 두목인가?
Let's go!
간다!
Drill Crush!
드릴 크러시!
He's reckless and not very bright, but he's still reliable.
저돌적이고 바보같지만 믿음직해
Oh, we must not forget Dag Shadow!
아, 잊어서는 안되는 또 한 사람, 다그 섀도우!
Are there more?!
아직도 있습니까?
Merging Fusion!
융합합체
(融合合體)
Dag Shadow!
다그 섀도우
I'll use this moment to let you know.
이 기회에 가르쳐 주지
Dag Shadow can transform to Shadow Dragon.
다그 섀도우는 섀도우 드래곤으로 변형할 수도 있어
Dragon Plasma Burn!
드래곤 플라즈마 번!
Because of this, as long as there is Dagwon, we aren't afraid of the aliens who are after Earth.
이런 이유로, 다그온이 있는 한 지구를 노리는 우주인 따위는 두렵지 않은 거야
I see!
호아악! 과연 그렇군요~
Anyway, Gaku, no, Mr. Manabu...
그건 그렇고, 가쿠...
아... 아니 아니, 마나부 님
just in case, what if the enemy comes to attack with a more gigantic robot?
만약에, 모두 다 거대화했다고 해도 적이 더욱 강력한 전투 메카로 습격해 온다면
Wouldn't Dagwon be able to face them even with their big forms in such cases?
아무리 다그온일지라도 상대가 안되지 않을까요?
You're worrying too much!
아아, 사서 걱정을 하는구만
Then let me tell you this.
그럼 들려주지
Dagwon's important secret.
다그온의 중요한 비밀을...
An important secret?
중요한 비밀?
Right. The important secret!
그래! 중요한 비밀을 말이야
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
So what is that important secret of Dagwon?
그래서, 다그온의 중요한 비밀이란 게...
Ehem! Let me announce!
에헴! 그럼 발표하도록 하지
Dagwon can do it once more after performing Merging Fusion!
융합합체한 다그온들은 한층 더!
Once more?
한층 더?
It can't be! Are you saying that they can combine once more?
설마, 그들이 한층 더 합체할 수 있다는 겁니까?
That's right!
정답이야!
It's even more powerful than Merging Fusion!
그리고 융합합체보다 훨씬 강해진다구!
Fire Rescue, Fire Ladder, Fire Jumbo.
파이어 레스큐, 파이어 래더, 파이어 점보
These 3 Dag Vehicles and Dag Fire can combine to form Fire Dagwon!
이 3기의 다그 비클과 다그 파이어가 합체해서 파이어 다그온이 되는 거야!
Blazing Fusion!
화염합체
(火炎合體)
Fire Dagwon!
파이어 다그온
Fire Hold!
파이어 홀드!
Fire Blade!
파이어 블레이드!
Finish!
피니쉬!
I see. No wonder why Zargoss Seijins were having difficulties taking over the Earth.
그렇군, 자고스 성인 놈들의 지구 침략이 생각보다 진행되지 않는 데에는 그런 이유가 있었군
Hey, I'm not done yet.
이봐, 이야기는 아직 끝나지 않았어
Next is Shadow Dagwon.
다음은 섀도우 다그온이야
Alright! Let's raid on the enemy, and we'll have a match with the boss character!
좋아! 이대로 적진에 쳐들어가서 단숨에 보스 캐릭터와 승부다!
Guard Wolf, Guard Tiger, Guard Hawk!
가드 울프, 가드 타이거, 가드 호크
These 3 Shadow Guards and Dag Shadow can combine to become Shadow Dagwon!
이 3체의 섀도우 가드와 다그 섀도우가 합체해서 섀도우 다그온이 되는 거야!
Mecha-beast Fusion!
기수합체
(機獸合體)
Shadow Dagwon!
섀도우 다그온
Final blow!
마지막이다!
The way of the spirit, the Kagemurasaki! (Purple Shadow)
명도 카게 무라사키(名刀影紫)!
Shadow Beast King Slash!
섀도우 아왕참(我王斬り)!
And time for the last and the best!
그리고 마지막(眞打)으로 등장!
(眞打 : 본문에 설명해 놓겠습니다.)
It's Super Liner Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온이야!
Super Chaining Fusion!
초중련합체
(超重連合體)
Super Liner Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온
Finishing move! Super Liner Crush!
필살! 슈퍼! 라이너! 크러시!
To know that Hydron failed to defeat them, they're strong just as I heard.
그 휴드론 성인이 이기지 못하다니 소문대로 만만치 않은 녀석들이군
Hey, are you listening to me?
이봐, 내 말 제대로 듣고 있어?
O- of course.
무, 물론입니다
Oh, that's right.
아, 맞다
I should tell you about the comrades of Dagwon.
다그온의 동료들에 대해서도 소개해야지
-Comrades?
-Right.
-동료 말입니까?!
-그래
First, we have a space swordsman, Lian!
먼저 첫번째는 우주 검사 라이안!
Ken Seijin?
검성인?!
Their planet was supposedly destroyed by Ark Seijin...
틀림없이 녀석들의 별은 아크 성인에게 멸망당했을 텐데...
That's why Lian came to the Earth.
그래서 라이안은 지구에 온 거야
To take down Ark Seijin.
아크 성인을 쓰러뜨리기 위해서 말야
Until the day comes to have revenge for his home planet, Lian will protect the Earth with Dagwon!
고향의 복수를 갚는 그 날까지 라이안은 다그온과 함께 지구를 지켜줄 거야
I told you having a comrade won't hurt.
동료가 있는 것도 나쁘진 않을 거라고 말했다
I'll come whenever you need me.
필요할 때에는 언제든지 달려오지
See you later.
그럼 이만...
I never thought there would be an alive Ken Seijin...
살아남은 검성인이 있을 줄이야...
Next is Gunkid, a Gundroid!
다음은 건드로이드 건키드!
Gundroid?
건드로이드라고?
Isn't it a robot made by Mekaju Seijin?
메카쥬 성인이 만든 로봇이잖아요
Yeah. While the alien who made him is bad, Gunkid himself is a good guy!
응, 만든 우주인은 나쁜 녀석이지만 건키드는 좋은 녀석이야
That's why he became a comrade of Dagwon and Lian's taking care of him!
그래서 다그온의 동료가 되서 라이안에게 귀여움을 받고 있어
Gunkid, Change!
건키드 체인지!
How could that damn Mekaju Seijin give such an outrageous weapon to them?!
메카쥬 성인 녀석, 터무니없는 걸 만들어 줬군
And the long waited climax begins right now!
그리고 지금부터가 클라이막~스!
Both Lian and Gunkid can become Dagwon's certain kill weapons.
라이안도 건키드도 파이어 다그온의 필살 무기가 된다구
What?!
그럴수가!
Shudder runs over the beautiful planet
아름다운 행성에 전율이 흐른다
Feeling the moment the storm is coming on
폭풍이 오는 순간을 느끼며
Just like a hero inside is awakening
마음 속에서 깨어나는 영웅과 같이
Let's go! Let's fly away! Don't look back again!
가자! 날아가자! 뒤돌아보지 마라!
Fire Lio Sword!
파이어 라이오 소드!
Dagwon... Keep on shining!! Dagwon!
다그온... 계속 빛나라! 다그온!
Get it on! It's the name of peace to love
지켜라! 사랑해야 할 평화의 이름
Dagwon... You know we are Dagwon!
다그온... 우리는 다그온!
Gunkid, Change!
건키드 체인지!
Get it on... Nobody can take our dreams away!
우리 꿈은 그 누구도 가져갈 수 없어!
Oh, please if you wanna win trust and courage
신뢰와 우정을 얻고 싶다면 꼭
Let's go! Infinity Cannon!
간다, 무한포(無限砲)!
Believe in believe in just believe in friendship, powerfully
믿어라 믿어라 우정을 믿어라 강력하게
Do the right thing forever, don't be afraid of damage
피해에 개의치 않고 끝까지 옳은 것을 해라
Fire!
파이어!
Go ahead, go ahead, just go ahead for the future to dream
나아가, 나아가, 쭉 나아가라! 꿈 속의 미래를 위해!
I see. I understood everything I didn't know before about Dagwon.
과연... 다그온에 관해 예상하지 못한 부분은 이해했다
Can I take that as I don't have to tell you more?
그럼, 더이상 설명하지 않아도 알겠지?
You can be relieved and live on Earth!
안심하고 지구에서 살라구
-I cannot.
-Why?
그럴 순 없지
Because... I...
왜냐하면... 나는...
came to bury Dagwon and destroy the Earth!
다그온을 매장하고, 지구를 파괴하기 위해 왔기 때문이다
You know, destroying planets is my hobby.
혹성 파괴는 내 취미라서 말이지
Then... then you're?!
그럼... 그럼, 너는?!
Right. I also was an alien prisoner from Sargasso.
그래, 나도 사르갓소의 죄수란다
Thanks to you, I found out how to destroy those Dagwon bastards once and for all!
네 덕분에 다그온 놈들을 끝장낼 방법을 찾았다
As I promised, let me give you a present.
약속대로 너에게 답례를 해 주마
How noisy it is! Who the heck is Gaku talking with this late at night?
정말 시끄럽네... 가쿠도 참 이 밤중에 누구랑 떠들고 있는 거야?
Die! Die! Die!
죽어라! 죽어라! 죽어라~!
Gaku!
가쿠!
Ma- Maria!
누, 누나!
A cockroach!
바퀴벌레!
Ma- Maria... the alien...
누나... 우주인...
Don't talk in your sleep and just hurry up and go to bed!
무슨 잠꼬대야?
얼른 잠이나 자!
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
kaze no naka no PRISM
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
-Mouser Seijin are taking all the food in the town.
-They look just like rats!
-마을의 식량을 먹어치우는 마우자 성인
-쥐를 쏙 빼닮았어!
The town is in a big panic as they take over!
우글우글 튀어나와서 마을은 대 패닉!
Even with Dag Tectors, they're too much!
이렇게 많아선 다그 텍터라도 어쩔 수 없다구!
-They have weak points.
-A weak point! What is it?
-녀석들에게도 약점이 있다
-약점! 뭐냐?
That is... a cat.
그건... 고양이다
I see. If people raise cats, they won't be able to come!
그렇군, 고양이를 기르면 녀석들은 다가오지 못하는구나!
Look! People are taking the stray cats!
봐라, 마을 사람들이 도둑고양이를 서로 빼았고 있어!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! The Day Cats Disappeared
다음회 용자지령 다그온
고양이가 사라지는 날
Cats are not a tool for humans!
고양이들은 인간의 도구가 아니야!
The Day Cats Disappeared
고양이가 사라지는 날